Guide to the Edward James Brown
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Records
  - (Box 28)
    4. Donald Stoke's interview with Brown
    5. Miscellaneous files (bibliographies, articles, letters)
    6. Tourist photos of Moscow
    7. Notebook, class notes or possibly lecture notes
    8. Photographs - Mayakovsky and other images
    9. Reprints of Brown's book reviews
  - (Box 29)
    1. Typescript copies of one of Brown's books; foldered in order found
    2. Typescripts of other articles and some notes and outlines
  - (Box 30)
    Assorted books, some by Brown, some by others with annotations by Brown
  - circa 1986, 1987 (Box 31)
    1. Computer disks, audio tapes, microfilm
    2. VHS tapes: Prof. R. Schupbach, 1987; Russian Tape #4, 1986
  - (Box 32)
    Small notebooks, note cards, slides of Moscow (7)
  - (Box 33)
    Books and articles (in Russian)
  - (Box 34)
    Oversize items: photograph of Mayakovsky; diploma
  - circa 1946 - 1955 (Box 35)
    1. Notebooks on thesis research
    2. Typescript chapters of thesis
    3. Bulletin of the Amer. Assoc. of Teachers of Slavic and East European Languages, 1948
    4. Brown's papers as a student
    6. General correspondence, 1946-55 (with some articles and photos)
    7. Publication agreement
    8. Papers by Brown's students
    [this box undergoing conservation treatment in the department]
  - 1956 (Box 36)
    Oversize - photographs of Russia (Moscow?) in 1956 (23 mounted on board)
Partial Correspondence Index
Abernathy, Robert 2 4
Agushi, Irina 2 5
Allen, Beverly 2 9
Allen, George R. 11 13
Allworth, Edward 2 6
Anderson, John O. 2 7
Anschuetz, Carol 2 8
Anschuetz, Carol 2 9
Armstrong, John A. 1 8
Armstrong, John A. 2 1
Armstrong, John A. 1 7
Arndt, Walter 2 10
Arndt, Walter 2 6
Arndt, Walter 2 7
Arndt, Walter 2 8
Arndt, Walter W. 2 5
Arnold, Samuel T. 2 3
Arnold, Samuel T. 2 11
Arnovitz, Benton 4 5
Avins, Carol 2 7
Avins, Carol 2 9
Barooshian, V. 3 8
Barooshian, Vahan 3 10
Barooshian, Vahan 3 11
Barry, Anne 3 8
Beebe, Maurice 10 4
Bell, J.G. 15 8
Bell, J.G. 14 15
Bell, Jess G. 3 12
Berlin, Isiah 11 16
Berliner, Joseph 1 2
Berliner, Joseph 1 3
Berliner, Joseph 1 4
Berliner, Joseph S. 1 7
Berliner, Joseph W. 1 5
Bethea, David M. 4 2
Birnbaum, Henrik 3 13
Birnbaum, Henrik 4 1
Black, C. E. 3 7
Blake, Patricia 3 7
Bliss, Zenas 3 7
Bocock, Maclin 4 2
Bok, Derek 7 14
Brenckle, Carol 3 11
Bristow, Eugene K. 3 12
Brown, Clarence 11 13
Brown, Clarence 3 11
Brown, Deming 10 3
Brown, Deming 10 4
Brown, Deming 11 13
Brown, Deming 11 4
Brown, Deming 15 1
Brown, Deming 3 6
Brown, Deming 3 7
Brown, Deming 3 8
Brown, Deming 3 9
Brown, Deming 4 1
Brown, Nathalie Babel 3 10
Bullitt, Margaret 3 11
Bullitt, Margaret 3 13
Bun, Mary Lucia 4 1
Bundy, McGeorge 11 15
Burkhardt, Frederick 2 2
Burks, R. V. 3 13
Bushnell, Kristine 3 13
Cadley, Lalor 12 10
Cadley, Lalor 13 6
Cadley, Lalor 13 7
Cadley, Lalor 4 12
Cadley, Lalor 5 1
Carden, Patricia 8 11
Carden, Patricia. 5 3
Cargill, Carol 5 1
Cargill, Carol 6 1
Cargill, Carol (?) 5 2
Carnochan, Bliss 7 14
Carroll, Joe 5 5
Carroll, Joe 5 3
Cassiday, Julie 5 6
Chambliss, William J. 4 10
Chase, William M. 5 5
Choate, Fred 5 5
Chukovskii, Kornei Ivanovich 4 10
Clark, Katerina 5 6
Clowes, Edith 5 6
Cohen, Stephen F. 5 5
Collins, Christopher 11 13
Collins, Christopher 4 10
Collins, Christopher 4 13
Collins, Christopher 5 1
Collins, Christopher 5 2
Condee, Nancy 5 5
Cooke, Brett 5 5
Couch, Herbert N. 16 5
Cox, Stephen 6 4
Damianov, Raiko 3 8
Darragh, Doyle 5 13
Darragh, Doyle 5 17
Davis, Marcia 5 11
Davis, Susan 5 13
Demetz, Peter 15 1
Demetz, Peter 15 1
Den, Tatiana P. 5 10
Den, Tatiana P. 5 11
Dette, Kasola 5 15
Donovan, Nancy 14 15
Dovlatov, Sergei 5 17
Drake, Sandra 5 13
Dugdale, Grant 3 10
Dulley, Bryan E. 5 8
Dunham, Vera 15 1
Dunham, Vera 5 13
Dunham, Vera 5 15
Dunham, Vera 5 16
Dunham, Vera 5 17
Dunham, Vera 5 18
Dunham, Vera 5 9
Dunlop, John B. 5 16
Dunlop, John B. 5 17
Edgerton, William 18 9
Edgerton, William 6 2
Edgerton, William B. 3 4
Edgerton, William B. 5 19
Edgerton, William B. 5 22
Edgerton, William B. 5 23
Edgerton, William B. 8 5
Edgerton, William B. 9 4
Eisen, Sam 18 10
Emerson, Caryl 6 3
English, Deirdre 6 2
English, Maurice 5 19
English, Maurice 5 20
English, Maurice 5 21
English, Maurice 5 24
English, Maurice 6 1
English, Maurice 6 2
Ermolaev, Herman 6 2
Fahey, John 9 6
Fanger, Donald 14 15
Fanger, Donald 15 1
Fanger, Donald 17 2
Fanger, Donald 6 10
Fanger, Donald 6 11
Fanger, Donald 6 12
Fanger, Donald 6 13
Fanger, Donald 6 14
Fanger, Donald 6 5
Fanger, Donald 6 9
Fanger, Donald 7 14
Fanger, Donald 7 3
Ferber, Vreneli 6 11
Ferber, Vreneli 6 8
Feinburg, Sylvia 6 13
Fisher, Jr., Ralph T. 1 2
Fisher, Jr., Ralph T. 1 8
Fisher, Jr., Ralph T. 2 1
Fisher, Jr., Ralph T. 6 9
Fisher, Jr., Ralph T. 1 3
Fisher, Jr., Ralph T. 1 4
Fisher, Jr., Ralph T.W. 1 5
Fisher, Ralph T. 4 8
Fisher, Ralph T. 4 9
Fizer, John 6 7
Folejewski, Zbigniew 6 7
Frnak, Joseph 18 10
Frnak, Joseph 6 10
Frnak, Joseph 6 13
Freidin, Gregory 6 14
Friedberg, Maurice 6 13
Fiedberg, Maurice 6 8
Friedberg, Maurice 8 10
Fulton, Margretta 7 12
Garrad, John 18 9
Garrad, John 6 19
Garrad, John 7 1
Garrad, John 7 2
Garrad, John 7 3
Garrad, John 7 4
Garrad, John G. 6 17
Gasparov, Boris 7 3
Gatto, Joseph A. 6 17
Gelpi, Albert 12 6
Gelpi, Albert 12 7
Gelpi, Albert 7 3
Gibian, George 15 1
Gibian, George 17 17
Gibian, George 18 10
Gibian, George 18 8
Gibian, George 5 1
Gibian, George 6 17
Gibian, George 6 18
Gibian, George 7 12
Gibian, George 7 2
Ginsburg, Michael 6 16
Ginzburg, Lidia Iakovlevna 7 3
Glasse, Antonia 6 17
Glasse, Antonia 7 1
Glasse, Antonia 7 2
Goldstein, Darra 7 2
Goldstein, Darra 7 3
Goscilo, Helena 7 3
Goscilo, Helena 7 4
Gray, Francine 7 1
Green, Joslyn 7 1
Greenleaf, Monika 7 4
Gregg, Richard 6 16
Grgich, Ielena 15 3
Gribble. Charles 6 18
Grimsted, Patricia 6 17
Grimsted, Patricia 6 19
Gruliow, Leo 4 8
Gruliow, Leo 4 9
Gucker, Frank T. 3 4
Guerard, Alexander (John Pearson) 13 9
Guss, Alexander 6 17
Gustafson, Richard F. 6 17
Harkins, William 7 5
Hasty, Patricia 2 6
Haywood, Max 7 11
Hazard, John 1 2
Hazard, John N. 2 3
Henry, Kathryn 7 14
Henry, Kathryn 7 15
Hodge, Tom 7 14
Holquist, James M. 7 14
Hunt, Priscilla 14 4
Iakobson, Roman 18 6
Ivanov, D. D. 15 3
Ivask, George 8 6
Jackson, Robert L. 8 19
Jakobson, Roman 11 13
Jakobson, Roman 7 10
Jakobson, Roman 7 9
James, Jean M. 8 17
Jovanovic, Michael 8 19
Junzhi Sih, Julia 8 18
Kagan-Kans, Eva 9 23
Kagan-Kans, Eva 9 7
Kagan-Kans, Eva 9 8
Kagan-Kans, Eva 9 9
Kallas, James Gus 9 10
Kaplan, Martin 9 11
Karlinsky, Simon 15 1
Karlinsky, Simon 9 11
Karlinsky, Simon 9 12
Kassof, Allen H. 9 9
Kassof, Allen 9 1
Keeney, Barnaby 3 7
Keeney, Barnaby 9 5
Keeney, Barnaby 9 6
Keeney, Barnaby C. 3 1
Keeney, Barnaby C. 2 11
Kellenberger, Hunter 13 4
Kellenberger, Hunter 9 5
Kellenberger, Hunter 9 6
Kellenberger, Hunter 9 6
Kellenberger, Hunter 2 11
Kennedy, Donald 12 8
Kern, Gary 9 10
Kern, Gary 9 11
Kharon, Ia. E. 18 12
Kharon, Iakov 7 11
Kharon, Iakov E. 2 6
King, Sara Knox 9 12
Kiziria, Dodona 13 3
Kiziria, Dodona 9 4
Kline, George 15 1
Kline, George 9 13
Kline, George 9 4
Kline, George 9 8
Knapp, Shoshana Milgram 9 12
Knudson, Charles A. 8 6
Kolb, Patricia 16 3
Korytuaia, S. 18 12
Koslow, J. 9 7
Kozlovskii, V. I. 15 3
Kramer, Mark 9 13
Krauskopf, Konrad B 9 14
Kretschmer, Doris 5 15
Krynski, John 9 5
Laqueur, Walter 9 20
Lehrman, Edgar H. 9 20
Leviash, Daniel 9 18
Lewis, Edgar G. 1 7
Libedinskii, Iurii Nokolaevich 9 6
Liubarskaia, B. 15 3
Lopez-Morillas, Juan 9 19
Lopez-Morillas, Juan 9 20
Lord, Albert B. 7 10
Loseff, Lev 9 25
Lur'e, F. 9 18
Lyman, R. W. 2 11
Lynch, Marybeth 9 24
Lynch, Marybeth 9 25
MacLean, G. R. 5 14
Maddock, Mary 10 12
Maguire, B. 10 6
Maguire, Bob 10 7
Maguire, Bob 10 8
Maguire, Bob 10 9
Maguire, Robert A. 4 1
Maiakovskii, Vladimir 10 1
Makarov, V. 10 9
Malmstad, John 10 9
Malone, David 10 8
Malone, David H. 10 6
Markov, Serge 10 12
May, William R. 3 5
McAuliffe, Nancy Anne 10 5
McCloskey, Paul N. 10 10
McClung, William J. 5 3
McLean, Hugh 10 12
McLean, Hugh 10 5
McLean, Hugh 10 8
McLean, Hugh 14 10
McLean, Hugh 16 4
McLean, Hugh 3 2
Mihailoff-Shelly, Lydia 15 3
Miller, Dolly 10 12
Milovscroff, Basil 10 4
Moody, C. 10 7
Morson, Saul 10 13
Mosher, Paul 18 8
Mulholland, Charles V. 10 4
Murav, Harriet 10 13
Murphy, Michael 10 12
Murphy, Michael 6 2
Nabokov, Mrs. Vladimir 11 7
Nazarova, L. 5 11
Newton, W. 11 10
Nicholson, Michael 11 8
Nilsson, Nils 11 13
Nilsson, Nils 11 6
Nivat, George 11 9
Oinas, Felix 12 3
Olcott, Anthony 11 17
Olcott, Anthony 12 1
Olcott, Anthony 12 2
Olcott, Anthony 12 3
Olcott, Anthony 12 4
Olcott, Martha 12 4
Olmsted, Emily 11 16
Orth, Samuel 11 16
Ovchrenko, Alexander 12 1
Paperno, Irina 13 11
Parker, William Riley 13 5
Pashin, Nicholas S. 13 7
Peeps, Stephen 12 7
Pekurovskaia, Asia 18 12
Pekurovskaya, Asya 12 6
Pekurovskaya, Asya 12 7
Pekurovskaya, Asya 12 8
Pe1covits, N. A. 15 5
Perloff, Marjorie 13 12
Peverieri, Wes 15 2
Pike, David 13 9
Pitzer, K.S. 2 11
Pratt, Mary 13 9
Probstein, Ronald 13 4
Proffer, Carl 13 10
Proffer, Carl 13 11
Proffer, Carl 13 5
Proffer, Carl 13 6
Proffer, Carl 13 7
Proffer, Ellendea 11 13
Proffer, Ellendea 13 10
Proffer, Ellendea 13 6
Putnam, John B 13 3
Queen, David 13 13
Quinn, Michael 13 14 0
Rabinowitch, Janet 14 5
Rabinowitch, Janet 8 10
Rabinowitch, Janet 8 11
Rabinowitch, Janet 8 8
Raevskii, Iu. S. 18 12
Reddaway, Darlene 14 5
Reddaway, Darlene 14 6
Reeve, Frank 13 19
Reeve, Helen (?) 13 19
Richter, Bodo 13 18
Rinkus, Jerome 14 1
Rinkus, Jerome 14 3
Rohrabacher, Dana 14 6
Rohrabacher, Dana 18 2
Rosengrant, Judson 14 6
Rosengrant, Sandra 14 3
Rosengrant, Sandra 14 4
Rosengrant, Sandra 14 5
Rosenthal, Charlotte 14 4
Rosenthal, Charlotte 14 5
Rosenthal, Charlotte 14 6
Ryan, John 8 11
Ryan, Lawrence V. 17 18
Ryan, Michael T. 14 6
Rydel, Christine 14 1
Rydel, Christine 14 2
Rydel, Christine 14 4
Saal, Christine 15 9
Scott, Cynthia 8 2
Shaw,1. T. 15 5
Sheldon, Richard (Dick) 16 1
Sheldon, Richard (Dick) 16 2
Sher, Benjamin 16 3
Sherwood, Mrs. Arthur 12 10
Sherwood, Mrs. Arthur 12 9
Shipley, Joseph T. 13 3
Sih, Julia Junzhi 16 2
Simmons, Ernest 15 8
Simmons, Ernest J. 15 4
Simmons, Ernest J. 15 6
Simmons, Ernest J. 15 5
Simms, John 17 2
Sixsmith, Martin 16 1
Solomon, Harold 15 4
Stender-Petersen, Ad. 13 16
Stilman, Leon 15 4
Sutton, Joseph 8 8
Talbott, Strobe 16 8
Talbott, Strobe 17 3
Taranovsky, Kiril 17 1
Tartar, Helen 17 2
Terras, Victor 17 2
Terrie, Henry 16 10
Thompson, John 16 5
Thompson, Terry 17 2
Thompson, Terry 17 3
Thompson, Terry 5 17
Titunik, LR. 17 2
Todd, William 12 7
Todd, William 17 1
Todd, William 17 2
Treadgold, Donald 14 12
Treadgold, Donald 15 6
Treadgold, Donald 15 7
Treadgold, Donald 15 8
Treadgold, Donald 16 11
Treadgold, Donald 16 6
Treadgold, Donald W. 1 2
Treadgold, Donald W. 1 3
Treadgold, Donald W. 1 4
Treadgold, Donald W. 1 5
Treadgold, Donald W. 1 6
Treadgold, Donald W. 2 5
Treadgold, Donald W. 11 13
Treadgold, Donald W. 3 8
Trifonov, Trifon 3 8
Turner, Gordan B. 4 8
Turner, Gordan B. 4 9
Turrentine, Lowell 17 2
Twarog, Leon 3 2
Ulanovskaya, Nadezhda 17 6
Unbegaun, Boris 17 5
Urnov, Drnitrii 17 7
Ushakova, Nina 17 6
Uspensky, Boris 17 6
Van Campen, Joseph 14 11
Van Campen, Joseph 14 5
Van Campen, Joseph 16 1
Van Campen, Joseph 17 13
Van Campen, Joseph A. 12 6
Van Campen, Joseph A. 14 8
Van Campen, Joseph A. 15 6
Van Campen, Joseph A. 3 8
Van Campen, Joseph A. 2 11
Van Campen, Joseph A. 5 3
van der Eng, J. 17 15
Van Erde, John 17 12
van Schooneveld, C. H. 10 11
van Schooneveld, C. H. 17 14
van Schooneveld, C. H. 17 9
van Schooneveld, C. H. 8 11
Vinogradov, V. V. 2 4
Von Wiren, Vera 17 13
Von Wiren, Vera 17 14
Walker, Barbara 18 3
Walker, Jim 17 17
Waller, Fletcher 6 13
Warner, Nicholas 18 2
Wasiolek, Edward 17 17
Weber, Harry 17 17
Weeks, Laura 17 20
Weeks, Walter J. 17 17
Weil, Irwin 17 17
Weil, Irwin 18 2
Wentworth, Linda 17 17
West, Jane 18 2
Whittaker, Jr., Robert T. 17 18
Wildman, Allan 17 16
Wildman, Allan 17 17
Wildman, Allan 18 2
Wiles, Timothy 18 1
Wilson, Natalia 17 18
Winger, Howard 17 16
Wiren, John R. 17 16
Wolfe, Bertram 15 1
Wood, Bryce 14 13
Wood, Bryce 15 5
Woodley, Tina 17 17
Worth, Dean 17 9
Worth, Dean 18 1
Wright, John W. 11 14
Wright, John W. 11 13
Yalom, Irvin D. 18 5
Zarniatine, L. 18 7
Zarniatine, L. 18 6